# **Steve Thompson**

Rockford, IL 61114 | Email: steve@sthmpsn.dev | Phone: 631-834-8881 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/steven-thompson-10a5071b | GitHub: github.com/sthmpsn | Portfolio: sthmpsn.dev

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer and experienced IT leader. Known for creative problem solving, ability to rapidly learn new applications and technologies, with strong leadership skills. Have been described as "the glue that holds the department together" and recipient of multiple "Pioneer", "Pathfinder", "Count on Me", and "One Team" awards demonstrating the ability to innovate, collaborate, and provide stellar service to internal and external clients.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Php, PowerShell, Perl, SQL

Frameworks & Technologies: Node, Express, Bootstrap, Vue, Laravel, Wordpress, React

Databases: Mongo, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Firebase

OS & Applications: Windows Server, RedHat Linux, Heroku, Atlassian Jira, Bitbucket, Crowd, and Confluence Data

Center editions, IBM ClearCase and ClearQuest, Coverity, Collaborator, Git, Adobe XD **Methods:** Configuration Management, SDLC, Continuous Improvement, Agile, Waterfall

#### **PROJECTS**

# Gifflix | Demo: https://gifflix.sthmpsn.dev | Code: github.com/sthmpsn/Gifflix

- Summary: A Giphy search that utilizes the giphy.com API and allows you to add desired search categories
- Role: Developer
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Ajax, Giphy API

# React Clicky Game | Demo: https://clickygame.sthmpsn.dev | | Code: github.com/sthmpsn/clicky-game

- Summary: Front-end React game with Simpsons theme that tests your memory
- Role: Developer
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, React

#### CYOA | Demo: cyoa-bc.herokuapp.com/ || Code: github.com/sthmpsn/cyoa

- **Summary**: The application is a create-your-own-adventure-style game boot camp theme.
- Role: Full Stack Developer
- **Technologies**: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Express-validate, Sequelize.js, bcryptjs, MySQL, Heroku, JawsDB, Gauge.js

## TryAthlete | Demo: my-try-athlete.herokuapp.com | | Code: github.com/sthmpsn/TryAthlete

- Summary: React app that helps people track their personal tri-athlete and fitness goals in a fun way
- Role: Project Manager, DB Architect, Full Stack Developer
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, React-Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Semantic-UI-React, React-Youtube

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Junior Web Developer | FMTC | Remote

October of 2020

- Lead Front-end developer for a critical internal business Web Application development from scratch
- Configure PHP Laravel Mix Webpack configurations to ensure project assets are built and minified
- Generate project build documentation and onboard new team members to the project
- Define intuitive folder structure and collaborate with the Senior Back End developer to determine logical Web and API routes
- Build the UI for the "from scratch" business application and present progress via weekly demos
- Generate front end Tests using Laravel Dusk

- Improve existing internal and customer facing application UI and UX
- Create wireframes and mockups using adobe XD to present to cross functional team for review
- Refactor front end code consisting of Php, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4 and Javascript as well as some backend code consisting of php Codeigniter framework
- Design and implement a new front end for a complete rebuild of our existing applications using Vue 3, Bootstrap 5, Sass, and Typescript.

# **Quality Assurance | Nucamp Coding Bootcamp | Remote**

June of 2020

- Provide Quality Assurance control for HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap course curriculum
- Establish a change control workflow using a kanban board to organize all change requests for each curriculum
- Test new node package versions for courses and provide recommendations to improve course material clarity and effectiveness

## Web Development Instructor | Nucamp Coding Bootcamp | Remote

May of 2020

• Instructor for Front-end Web development boot camp classes including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.

# Principal IT Analyst | BAE Systems, Inc. | Remote

2016 - 2020

- Architect and deploy a set of modern Engineering Development Lifecycle tools consisting of Atlassian Crowd, Jira, Bitbucket, and Confluence resulting in an application support cost savings of \$3M
- Manage a cross-sector team consisting of three different sectors and 5 different business areas which
  resulted in a reduction of ticket redirects, increased awareness of security vulnerabilities, and the ability
  to rapidly deploy upgrades to standardized applications
- Team Lead and subject matter expert of 7 applications consisting of 6 team members for 3000+ users

## Senior IT Analyst | BAE Systems, Inc. | Austin, TX

2012 - 2016

- Lead IT initiatives such as server and license consolidation effort leading to \$420K in annual savings.
- Deployed engineering tools that resulted in over \$300K in defect detection hours
- Gather requirements, plan, test, execute, and maintain SDLC and other engineering applications

## IT Analyst II | BAE Systems, Inc. | Greenlawn, NY

2009 - 2012

- Provide ClearCase and ClearQuest support for 2000+ Engineers located at geographically dispersed sites
- Plan closed area deployments of applications and provide tool training to ensure tool adoption success

#### Computer Systems Analyst II | BAE Systems, Inc. | Greenlawn, NY

2004 - 2008

- Manage 20+ programs in the Software Engineering department with 150 Software Engineers
- Create Software Development and Configuration Plans for projects exceeding \$400K in sales
- Ensure software processes comply with CMMI level 5 certification and participate in DOD audits
- Develop branching strategies and establish software baselines to ensure integrity

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Business Administration, Information Systems Management: Dowling College, Oakdale, NY Bachelor of Arts, Business Administrator of Information Technology: Briarcliffe College, Patchogue, NY

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

SW Product Management: University of Alberta, via coursera.com

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

CompTIA Network+ -ID#: COMP001020665277 CompTIA Security+ - ID#: COMP001020665277

ITIL v3 Foundations – ID#: 979888